Howard Jess

Web Application Software Developer/Engineer

hjess@mail.com 206.412.9924

Synopsis

I'm an experienced client-side web application developer, who really enjoys working in a small collaborative team environment. Ideally, the team and company culture place highest emphasis on customers, employees, and providing a social good, along with keeping an eye on the bottom line. Interests and abilities include interface design and implementation, especially in the areas of accessibility and feature tracking.

Capabilities

- In-depth understanding of Javascript, HTML and CSS, as well as frameworks like <u>Angular</u> and <u>SASS</u>.
- Adept with tools such as Git, Grunt, Jira, npm and Subversion, and processes like Agile, Scrum, and Kanban.
- At ease working as part of a team or as an individual contributor.
- Experience in traditional commercial software development as well as web applications.

Experience

Rosetta Stone (after April 2013 Livemocha aquisition)

Front-end Web Application Developer

November 2012 → *present*

Developer for Rosetta Stone's <u>Advanced English for Business</u> language-learning application, and <u>Livemocha</u>, a social community-based language-learning application. Achievements and projects completed include:

- Password reset/recovery
- · User profile management
- · Partner connections
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics
- System rewrite from Sproutcore to AngularJS.

Optify, Inc.

Front-end Software Engineer
September 2011 → October 2012

UI developer for Optify's *Inbound Marketing* software suite, a <u>SAAS</u> tool for B2B marketers. Achievements and projects completed include:

- Customer site "Landing Page" editor/publisher
- Contact Manager & Email Manager tools
- Analytics, using <u>Mixpanel Analytics</u>
- Rewrote UI coding standards document, and overhauled the Javascript library namespace

Cobalt.com, Inc.

Senior UI Developer

September 2009 → September 2011

Lead UI developer on Cobalt's *New Products* team, charged with creating and delivering innovative website products for sale to auto manufacturers and dealers. Achievements and projects completed include:

- Embedded <u>Google maps</u> for location pages
- Facebook and Twitter publishing and feed widgets
- Embedded <u>YouTube</u> player/playlist handler
- Initial implementation of front-end unit testing using <u>istestdriver</u>

Howard Jess

Web Application Software Developer/Engineer

hjess@mail.com 206.412.9924

Wetpaint.com, Inc.

UI Web Developer September 2008 → July 2009

UI developer for Wetpaint's "build your own wiki" system. Achievements and projects completed include:

- · Enhanced messaging forum system
- Access to PayPal's <u>recurring billing</u> system
- User authentication using Facebook Connect
- · Conversion from home-grown library to iQuery

Cardomain Networks, Inc.

Web Developer

September 2006 → September 2008

Front-end specialist for Cardomain's "facebook for car enthusiasts" applications. Achievements and projects completed include:

- Homepage and navigation overhaul, with complete site re-layout for uniform ad placements, using Perl/TTK
- Member group subsystem, using Ruby on Rails
- Immersed in all aspects of <u>Agile development</u>, including story estimation, pair programming, <u>TDD</u>, sprint demos, and frequent releases

Skills

Tools:

Ant, Atom, AWK, Bourne/Korn shell, GIMP, Git, Grunt, Make, Sublime Text, Subversion

Languages:

Javascript, TCL, C

Systems:

Linux, Unix, Mac OS/X, Windows

Technologies:

AJAX, AngularJS, CSS (Less, SASS/SCSS), DOM, HTML, HTTP, i18n/I10n, jQuery, MVC, REST, TCP/IP

Development:

Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Education

Northwestern University

B.A., Economics